<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<!--
  ~ Copyright [2014] [Christian Loehnert, krampenschiesser@gmail.com]
  ~ Licensed under the Apache License, Version 2.0 (the "License");
  ~ you may not use this file except in compliance with the License.
  ~ You may obtain a copy of the License at
  ~
  ~     http://www.apache.org/licenses/LICENSE-2.0
  ~
  ~ Unless required by applicable law or agreed to in writing, software
  ~ distributed under the License is distributed on an "AS IS" BASIS,
  ~ WITHOUT WARRANTIES OR CONDITIONS OF ANY KIND, either express or implied.
  ~ See the License for the specific language governing permissions and
  ~ limitations under the License.
  -->

<chapter>
    <title>General information</title>
    <section>
        <title>About idnadrev</title>
        <para>
            Project idnadrev is a task, information and life management system aimed for personal use.
            There will be a
            <emphasis>PC(java)</emphasis>
            and a feature reduced
            <emphasis>mobile(android)</emphasis>
            version.
            The PC version will also act as a server for the mobile version.
            As for task management it follows common principles similar to GTD.
            So the user can
            <emphasis>collect any information, documents, media whatever...</emphasis>
            This stuff can be processed/reviewed in order to create
            <emphasis>tasks/projects</emphasis>
            or<emphasis>knowledge</emphasis>.
            A knowledge item can be linked to tasks but can also exist standalone.
            <emphasis>Tags</emphasis>
            and
            <emphasis>Categories</emphasis>
            help you to find your relevant knowledge items.
            The
            <emphasis>emotion tracking</emphasis>
            system(if activated) will help you to identify what kind of task(work, leisure, sports etc.)
            makes you feel good or bad and help/suggest the next best task for your current mood.
            The
            <emphasis>food planner</emphasis>
            will help you to keep track of your daily calorie consumption and nutrition.
            It will provide you with a shopping list and your own recipes.
            The
            <emphasis>money tracker</emphasis>
            will help you to keep track of the amount of money you spend as well as help you with
            saving up money for bigger projects.
            A
            <emphasis>vocabulary trainer</emphasis>
            will help you to learn your favourite languages or just to train
            your brain in remembering things.
            For each feature there will be
            <emphasis>predefined reports</emphasis>
            helping you to analyse yourself.
        </para>
    </section>

    <section>
        <title>Information/Thought</title>
        <para>
            You can collect anything you want which might be a future task, project, or a knowledge item.

            After collecting those information you can process them and transfer them into tasks or knowledge items.

            You can of course always create knowledge items or tasks immediately.
        </para>
    </section>
    <section>
        <title>Task</title>
        <para>
            A task is the central item of idnadrev. It can be a child of another task which makes its parent to a
            project.
            It can be recurring, scheduled, delegated, the typical stuff.
            They can be grouped by location and topic.
            There is a time tracking method that gives you feedback on the time estimated and spend.
            This time tracking can also be adjusted to give you a custom break timetable.
        </para>
    </section>

    <section>
        <title>Knowledge</title>
        <para>
            A knowledge item is quite widespread.
            It basically exists of text combined with files.
            You can mark a knowledge item with tags and categories for easier finding.
        </para>
    </section>

    <section>
        <title>Tags and Categories</title>
        <para>
            You can define tree-formed categories and give tags to your knowledge items
            for easier finding via browsing and searching.
        </para>
    </section>

    <section>
        <title>Vocabulary trainer</title>
        <para>

        </para>
    </section>

    <section>
        <title>Emotion tracking</title>
        <para>

        </para>
    </section>

    <section>
        <title>Food planner</title>
        <para>

        </para>
    </section>

    <section>
        <title>Money tracker</title>
        <para>

        </para>
    </section>
</chapter>